Mahipal Vennavaram

Hyderabad, 500088 | 8143149749 | mahipalvinny30@gmail.com

Professional Summary

Motivated **AWS DevOps Engineer** with **7.5 years** of progressive experience in IT Industry in the field of automation, software configuration management and cloud services.. Energetic self-starter and team builder. Navigates high-stress situations and achieves goals on time.

Experience

PLATFORM ENGINEER | 01/2022 - Current

Quantiphi Analytics Solutions pvt ltd - Bangalore

- Coordinate/assist developers with establishing and applying appropriate branching, labeling /naming conventions using GIT source control.
- Resolving issues in the Dev, QA, and Prod environments related to the Platform.
- Creating Jenkins pipelines for Dev, QA, and Prod environments.
- Initiating alarms in CloudWatch service for monitoring the server's performance, CPU Utilization, disk usage etc. to take recommended actions for better performance.
- Implemented permission boundary in all our resources according to the client requirement.
- Created new microservices with cloudformation template according to the requirements of the project.
- Running build jobs and integration tests on Jenkins.
- Branching, Merging, Release activities on Version Control Tool GIT.
- Used GitHub as version control to store source code and implemented Git for branching and merging operations for Java Source Code.
- Responsible for monitoring the AWS resources using Cloud Watch.
- Exceeded client expectations for software function, performance and features by working closely with development and quality assurance teams.
- Aligned projects with requirements and specifications to deliver above-benchmark results.
- Built and maintained internal tools, evaluating performance and updating.
- Confirmed software certifications remained valid and up-to-date for continued operational compliance.
- Reinforced disaster recovery operations and performed periodic data back-ups to strengthen network security.
- Regularly assessed IT infrastructure for best-possible security and efficiency.
- Directed computer network access and use by controlling master consoles.
- Created and executed automation processes, enhancing application scalability and functionality.
- Quickly responded to and resolved debugging issues within production systems, minimising error and risk.
- Built effective pipelines and enhanced production infrastructure through targeted database and cluster management.
- Used Docker and Kubernetes to manage, scale and update containers for improved automation possibilities.

ASSOCIATE SYSTEM ENGINEER | 06/2021 - 01/2022

Aquity Solutions - Hyderabad

- Diagnosed hardware and software issues, implementing action to prevent reoccurrence.
- Confirmed software certifications remained valid and up-to-date for continued operational compliance.
- Installed and configured various software and hardware for smooth-running systems operation.
- Regularly assessed IT infrastructure for best-possible security and efficiency.
- Resolved issues and escalated problems with knowledgeable support and quality service.
- Operated server management tools for patching, monitoring and backup activity.
- Delivered reliable support for all server-class systems.
- Installed and maintained IT equipment and software to meet workflow requirements.
- Owned support tickets using IT management system Impulse for assigning and escalating.

HEALTHCARE DOCUMENTATION ASSOCIATE | 12/2015 - 06/2021

Aquity Solutions - Hyderabad

- Thrived in fast-paced environment with energy and enthusiasm.
- Demonstrated consistent hard work and dedication to achieve results and improve operations.
- Built and maintained courteous and effective working relationships.
- Produced high-volume orders to effectively meet customer demand.
- Collaborated with team members to achieve target results.

Core Qualifications

- AWS, Jenkins, Github, Bitbucket
- Ansible, Terraform
- ECS, Docker
- Jfrog artifactory, JIRA, Confluence
- Configuration management
- Software development life cycle
- System administration
- Operational support
- Security monitoring

- Application scaling
- Amazon Web Services configuration
- Microservices architecture
- Docker understanding
- Cloud service configuration
- Agile methodologies
- Optimising and performance tuning
- Scripting Shell, Python
- Knowledge on Kubernetes

Education

SR Engineering College - Warangal, TG | B.Tech

Electronics & Communication Engineering, 2015

Additional Information

Overall 7.5 years of professional experience in IT Industry and has experience of 2 years as a AWS DevOps Engineer in the field of automation, software configuration management and cloud services. Experienced working in AWS Cloud Computing platform and many dimensions of scalability including EC2, S3, API gateway, Cognito, Load balancers, ECS, Lambda, DynamoDB, cloudformation template, Cloud Watch. Manage and configure AWS services as per the business needs (ELB, SNS, EC2, Route53, S3, Cloud Watch, IAM, VPC). Implemented dockerfile and deployed microservices on ECS Cluster. Created Elastic Load Balancer with Listeners added with target group. Creating Auto Scaling Groups with Launch Templates and Launch Configurations. Creating Cloud watch Monitoring Alerts using Alarm with Multiple Metrics. Managing S3 with by applying Replication and LifeCycle Rules. Built S3 buckets and managed policies for S3 buckets and used S3 bucket and Glacier for storage and backup on AWS. Creating VPC with Public and Private Subnets along with RouteTables. Managing EBS Volumes taking Snapshots at regular intervals. Worked on JIRA for defect/issues logging & tracking

and documented all my work using CONFLUENCE. Provided support to the technical escalation from the team and Coordinate service calls and requests with team members where necessary.

Projects

· Project #1: Strategic OEM(Liberty General Insurance)

Duration: Jan, 2022 - Oct, 2022

· Project #2: Liberty Mutual Insurace East Region

Duration: Nov,2022 – till present